Education College Records (Preliminary Inventory) 1911-1958
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
- General Office Records, including correspondence, budgets, course materials, and conference proceedings, 1911-1958; 1
  - Publishers – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Publishers – Printed Forms and Directory of Publishers – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Pullman Schools – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Seattle – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Spokane Public Schools – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - State Board Rulings (Teacher Certification) Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Teacher Education and Professional Standards Meetings – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Committees – Inter-Institutional Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Committee- Teacher Education – State Board of Education – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Conferences and Conventions – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Courses at Other Colleges – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Educators Washington Dispatch – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 23)
  - Katterle 1952 (Box 24)
  - Katterle (Box 24)
  - Katterle - Union Gap investigation (Box 24)
  - Correspondence File (thesis) 1956 (Box 24)
  - Cross-Tubs 1956 (Box 24)
  - Houses – Follow-up 1951 (Box 24)
  - Elementary and Secondary (no year) (Box 24)
  - Ellensburg Public Schools – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Federal Aid to Education – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Health – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Inland Empire – Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Legislature - Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles In-Service Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - National Educational Association - Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Fellowship Application - Prior to Sept. 1950 (Box 25)
  - Home Economics 1949-1950 (Box 25)
  - Industrial Arts 1949-1950 (Box 25)
  - Library 1949-50 (Box 25)
  - Reading Clinic 1946-1950 (Box 25)
  - Secondary Education 1949- 9/1150 (Box 25)
  - Science Education 1949-1950 (Box 25)
  - Visual Aids 1949-1950 (Box 25)
  - Vocational Education 1949-50 (Box 25)
  - Agriculture Education 1952 (Box 25)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1951-1952 (Box 25)
  - Bulletins – W.S.C. Staff 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Community College Service 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Administrative Council 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Dean of Students 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Executive Committee 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Graduate Studies 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Improvement of Instruction 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Space Priority 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Thesis – JM Lee Only 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Examinations 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Foreign Students 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Form Letters and Announcements 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Degrees and Certificates – Administrators Credentials 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Degrees and Certificates – New Masters Correspondence 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Degrees and Certificates – New Masters Miscellaneous 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Doctorial and Doctorial Candidates 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Masters and Masters Candidates 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Deferred Majors 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Majors by Classes and Departments (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Miscellaneous 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Predictions 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Reports on Majors and Double Majors 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Enrollment – Small Classes 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Inquiries – General Policy, Miscellaneous 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Interdepartmental Memos 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Junior Colleges 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Recommendations 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - KWSC 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Library 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Library – Current Acquisitions Lists 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Non-Faculty Personnel and Time Slips 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Phi Delta Kappa 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Physical Education 1952-53 (Box 25)
  - Placement Bureau 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Placement Bureau Follow-up 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Publicity (School of Education) 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Reading Clinic 1952-53 (Box 25)
  - Registrar 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Registrar – Distribution of Grades 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Registration 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Research Council 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - President’s Office – C. Clement French - 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - President’s Office – S.T. Stephenson 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - President’s Office – William A. Pearl 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Tests 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Scholarships – John Hay Fellowships 1951-52 (Box 25)
  - Veteran’s Administration 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - School of Education General 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Scholarships – Chi Omega Scholarships 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Scholarships – Foreign Students 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Scholarships – Miscellaneous 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Scholarships – PTA – Correspondence and Inquiries 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Staff – Appointments and Resignations 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Staff – Education Graduate Faculty Memos and Minutes 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Staff – Recommendations for Promotions, Policy, Retirement, Tenure, 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Staff – WSC Resident Instructional 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Staff – Instructor’s Programs 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Student Teaching – Correspondence 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - AACTE – Alberta, Canada Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - AACTE – Correspondence Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - AACTE – Bulletins Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - AACTE – Mailing List Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - AACTE – Reports, Budgets, Minutes Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - American Legion Education Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Civil Defense Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Sunnyside Clippings 1952 (Box 26)
  - Civil Defense Information Kit 1952 (Box 26)
  - Teacher Education Committee – Minutes of May 1951 Meeting (Box 26)
  - Educators Washington Dispatch Sept. 1951 to date (Box 26)
  - Ford Foundation Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Inland Empire Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Kellogg Foundation Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Legislature Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - National Education Association (N.E.A.) Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Publishers Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Richland Schools Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - School Buildings Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Spokane Public Schools Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - State Board Rulings (Teacher Certification) Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - State Department – Wendell Allen Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - State Department – Boydie Rich Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - State Department – Peal Wannamaker Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - State Department of Public Instruction – Miscellaneous - Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Sunnyside Crisis 1952 (Box 26)
  - Sunnyside Schools - Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Wash. Educ. Association Sept. 1951 – date (Box 26)
  - Buildings and Grounds Agric. Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Buildings and Grounds School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Buildings and Grounds – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Central Stores – Agric. Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Central Stores – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Central Stores – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Duplication and Mailing – Agric. Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Duplication and Mailing – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Duplication and Mailing – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Photographic Lab – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Photographic Lab – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Printing Department – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Printing Department – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Student Counseling Center – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Student Counseling Center – Summer Session 1951 (Box 26)
  - Utilities and Construction School of Education and Summer Session 1951 (Box 26)
  - Visual Aids – School of Education 1952 (Box 26)
  - Visual Aids – Summer Session 1952 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Advertisement 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Assistant Teaching Contracts 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment – Lee Allen Hardware: American Reedcraft Corp., Broadhead Garrett Co. A-B 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment C-F 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment G-M 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment N-R 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Professional Services Rendered 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Service Contracts and Repair Bills 1951 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Subscribe Fees and Assoc. Dues 1950 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment – Student Bookstore 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Travel Tickets 1952 (Box 26)
  - Off Campus Requisitions – Equipment S-W 1952 (Box 26)
  - Staff Applications – Forms – “No Vacancies” 1951-1952 (Box 26)
  - Fellowship Applications 1951-52 (Box 26)
  - Art Educ. 1949 (Box 26)
  - Pakistan – Applications for Employment 1955 (Box 26)
  - State Department – Vocational Education 1957 (Box 26)
  - Small High Schools 1956 (Box 26)
  - University Study – High School and College Success 1950 (Box 26)
  - Ryder Bill 1955 (Box 26)
  - Travel Expense Vouchers – School of Education Faculty 1956-57 (Box 27)
  - A-C Bookstore 1956-57 (Box 27)
  - Budget – Request for Biennium 1955-57 (Box 27)
  - Budget – Biennial Reports – Current – 1954 (Box 27)
  - Catalogue – Final Draft 1956-58 (Box 27)
  - Catalogue Changes – for Next General Catalogue 1956-58 (Box 27)
  - Committee – Academic Committee 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Committee – Educational Policies 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - E.P.C. 1954-1955 (Box 27)
  - Committee – Scholarship Standards 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Committee Graduate Studies 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Courses – Internship in School Administration (Ed. 590) 1957 (Box 27)
  - Future of WSC and Functions 1954 (Box 27)
  - Guidance Position – Applications and Other Correspondence 1956 (Box 27)
  - Elementary Position – Applications and Other Correspondence 1956 (Box 27)
  - M-R Placement Bureau 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Presidents Office – C. Clement French 1954-55 (Box 27)
  - Presidents Office – S. Town Stephenson 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Scheduling 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Scheduling 1956-57 (Box 27)
  - Follow-Up Committee-Staff 1957 (Box 27)
  - Staff-Bulletins, Memorandums, 1955-56 – Notices, Etc. (Box 27)
  - Presidents Office Sept. 1953-Sept. 1954 – S.T. Stephenson (Box 27)
  - Presidents Office – S. Town Stephenson (Box 27)
  - State Department – Miscellaneous 1956-57 (Box 27)
  - State Department – Oregon 1956 (Box 27)
  - Follow-Up Trip, 1956-57 (Box 27)
  - Non-Faculty Personal 1955-56 (Box 27)
  - Presidents Office – C. Clement French 1955-57 (Box 27)
  - Dean S. Town Stephenson 1956-57 (Box 27)
- Summer Session Records, College of Education, 2
  - Summer Session Routine and Forms 1944 (Box 27)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – General (Box 27)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Payroll and Contracts (Box 27)
  - United Air Lines Scholarships 1945 (Box 27)
  - Summer Session Payroll and Contracts 1942 (Box 27)
  - Summer Session – 1945 – Application for Teachers (Box 28)
  - Summer Session 1945 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session Catalog – 1945 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session Dept. Costs – Salaries 1945 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1945 – General (Box 28)
  - Summer Session High School Classes ‘45 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session 1945 Home Economics (Box 28)
  - Summer Session Mailing List 1945 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session High School Classes 1944 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Home Economics (Box 28)
  - Late Enrollments and Special Considerations 1944 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session Library (Box 28)
  - Summer Session Mailing List 1944 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Mailing List (Box 28)
  - Sumer Session – 1944 – Speech Camp (Box 28)
  - Summer School – 1944 – County Directories with Out of State Teachers Listed (Box 28)
  - State College of Washington – College of Engineering – Course ME Education 181 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Advertisement (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Budget, Expenditures (Box 28)
  - Summer Session 1944 Enrollment (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Pre-Flight Course (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Education Conference (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Applications for Teachers (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Catalogue (Box 28)
  - Summer Session – 1944 – Correspondence (Box 28)
  - Ed. Classes with Visiting Instructions 1944 (Box 28)
- College of Education, In Service Teacher Preparation (ISTP) Records, 3
  - In-Service Training Program 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - 1945-46 I.S.T.P. Plans (Box 28)
  - In-Service Training 1946 (Box 28)
  - In-Service-Adams County 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - Asotin County 1946 (Box 28)
  - Douglas County 1946 (Box 28)
  - In-Sev-Grant Co. 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - Lincoln Co. 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - Okanogan County 1946 (Box 28)
  - Pend Oreille County 1945 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. Stevens Co. 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - In-Sev-Whitman Co. 1945-46 (Box 28)
  - Yakima Co. 1944-45- I.S.T.P. (Box 28)
  - Monthly Reports 1944-45 (Box 28)
  - Okanogan County 1944-45 (Box 28)
  - Asotin County – 44-45 (Box 28)
  - Walla Walla County 1944 (Box 28)
  - Douglas County 1944-45 (Box 28)
  - State Dept. 1944-45 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous 1944-45 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – General 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. Reports 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. State Department Correspondence 1943-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Lincoln Co. 1945 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. Stevens County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Yakima County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Okanogan County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Whitman County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Chelan County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Franklin County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - I.S.T.P. – Benton County 43-44 (Box 28)
  - In-Service Training Program 1945 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1940 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1939 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1938 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1937 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1936 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1935 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1934 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1933 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1932 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1931 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1930 (Box 28)
  - Credentials – 1929 (Box 28)
  - Student Staff (Box 29)
  - Library Practice (Box 29)
  - 100 Books Every Child Should Know (Box 29)
  - Publications (Box 29)
  - Outline of Complete Program of Studies of Toppenish Junior-Senior High School 1941-42 (Box 29)
  - Education Ed. 12 1946 (Box 29)
  - Cartoons 1949 (Box 29)
  - Intercultural Relations 1949 (Box 29)
  - Material From Ross Township School Dist. 1947 (Box 29)
  - Community 1948 (Box 29)
  - Summer Session Programs in Wash. Schools 1949 (Box 29)
  - Audio-Visual Aids References 1949 (Box 29)
  - Health 1949 (Box 29)
  - Latin (no year) (Box 29)
  - Materials Ordered for Library 1949 (Box 29)
  - UNESCO Pamphlets 1949 (Box 29)
  - United Nations 1949 (Box 29)
  - Primary Activities 1949 (Box 29)
  - Materials to Consider 1949 (Box 29)
  - Articles (Box 29)
  - Correspondence on Materials Requested 1949 (Box 29)
  - Materials to Order 1949 (Box 29)
  - NEA 1948 (Box 29)
  - A.A. Cleveland – Special Correspondence 1945 (Box 29)
- Leslie Chisholm Correspondence, 1937-1941, 4
  - A-B (Box 30)
  - C-D (Box 30)
  - E-G (Box 30)
  - H-L (Box 30)
  - M-N (Box 30)
  - P-R (Box 30)
  - S (Box 30)
  - T-Z (Box 30)
  - Summer Session Eduction Conference, 1945 (Box 30)
- College of Education, Class Grade Records Books, 5
  - The Teacher’s Improved Class Book (16 books) (Box 31)
  - Class Record Books, Various, 1916-1948 (142 books, about half are blank on outside) (Box 31)